Guide to the Clarence Irving Lewis Papers, 1933-1967
Department of Special Collections
Clarence Irving Lewis Papers,
1933-1967
Special Collections M0174
Lewis, Clarence Irving, 1883-1964.
14.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Andrew K. Lewis, 1966, 1980; articles about Lewis given by Fernando R. Molina, 1982.
Scope and Content
This collection contains: the correspondence of CLARENCE IRVING Lewis, PHILOSOPHY PROFESSOR (or about Lewis) dating from 1953 through 1967; the lecture notes Lewis used for his Philosophy courses; the manuscripts of Lewis' books such as Mind and the World Order; manuscripts of Lewis' papers; reprints of writings by and about Lewis; annotated/(by Lewis) books of Philosophy such as Kants Critique of Judgment; a bibliography of Philosophic works used by Lewis (on index cards). An extensive listing of the material is contained in the notebook by Robb Crist.
Biographical Note
Clarence Irving Lewis - Professor of Philosophy
Born April 12, 1883, Stoneham Massachusetts
Education AB Harvard, 1906 PhD 1910 LHD University of Chicago 1941
Married Mabel Maxwell Graves, Jan. 1, 1907 Children: Irving Maxwell, Margaret Maxwell, David Edson, Andrew Kittredge
Teacher High School English 1905-6
Instructor University of Colorado, 1906-8 (English)
Inst. and Asst. Prof. University of California 1911 - 20 (Philosophy)
Lecturer & Asst. Prof. & Prof. of Philosophy Harvard, 1920 -
Member of: American Philosophic Association, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, American Philosophic Society, British Academy, Phi Beta Kappa
Author of: Survey of Symbolic Logic, 1918 Mind and the World Order 1929 Symbolic Logic with C.H. Langford) 1932 An Analysis of Knowledge and Valuation 1946
Died: [UNK]
Container List
- Lewis, C.I. Papers Corresp. 1953-54 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lewis, C.I. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence Jan. - April 8,1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence April 11 to 11 Aug. 59 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence 20 Aug. - Dec. 59 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence Jan. - May 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence June - Dec. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence Jan. - Apr. 1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence May. - Dec. 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence Jan. - May 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence June - Dec. 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence 1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence 1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Misc. Correspondence Volume 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Memorabilia. May 1919 to Sept. 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Memorabilia. May 1919 to Sept. 1928 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Memorabilia. May 1928, May-1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Memorabilia. May 1928, May-1948 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Letters Jan. 1940 - Sept. 1948 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Memorabilia July 14, 1948 through Nov. 4, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Memorabilia July 14, 1948 through Nov. 4, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Memorabilia Sept. 1954 through May 14, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Library of living philosophers, Schilpp (Vol. 0) (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Library of living philosophers, Schilpp (Vol. 0) (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Library of living philosophers, Schilpp (Vol. 0) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Library of living philosophers, Schilpp (Vol. 1) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Library of living philosophers, Schilpp (Vol. 1) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Library of living philosophers, Schilpp (Vol. 2) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Library of living philosophers, Schilpp (Vol. 2x) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- On Potentials and Conditional Statements Volume 2xa, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Semantics 'Desirable' Volume 2xa, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- "Last Chapter"-- Or next to Last: We Approach the Normative Finalities 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Chapter IV: On Kant Volume 4, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Chapter IV: On Kant Volume 4, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- "The Good and Bad in Experience: Prolegomena" Early drafts May 1963 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- "The Good and Bad in Experience: Prolegomena" Early drafts May 1963 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- "Experience and the Good" With Early Drafts May-Nov. 1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- "Experience and the Good" With Early Drafts May-Nov. 1961 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- "Right acts and the Right to Do" (Vol. 5) (Box 4, Folder 5)
- "Criticism of Kantian Subjectivism" and "Logic"(Vol. 5) (Box 4, Folder 6)
- "Possible 'Collected Papers'" and "Ethics and Logical" Ch. 2 (Vol. 5a) (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Appendix to Ch. 2'" and "Pertinent to Modal Calculus and Ethics" (Vol. 5a) (Box 4, Folder 8)
- "Note about Free Will'", "Do not Believe what is Logically Impossible", and "Logical and Ethical Directives" (Vol. 5a) (Box 4, Folder 9)
- "Invention and Extention...'", "On Metaphysics", and "Science as Informational..." (Vol. 5a) (Box 4, Folder 10)
- "Semantics and Logic of the Impperative'"and "The Normative" (Vol. 6) (Box 4, Folder 11)
- "Chapter 5: The Right'"and "The Normative" (Vol. 6) (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Two Drafts of "Chapter 5: The Right'"and "On Subjectivism" (Vol. 6) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- "The Syntax and Logic of the Imperative" (Vol. 6) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- "Discarded" 1961, Five Versions of: "The Second Question in Ethics: Ethical Theory" 1960, "Ethics and Theory of Ethics" 1961 (Vol. 8a) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- "Chapter 3: Deliberate Acts" On Scientific Concepts 1962, On Behavior (Vol. 8a) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- "Ethics and Ethical Theory" 1960, "Practical Philosophy" 1961 (Vol. 7) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- "The Logic of Directives" May 1961 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- "Wide View and Narrow View" Apr. 1961 (Vol.8) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Two drafts of:"Chapter one: The Field of Ethics" Apr.- Sept. 1961 (Vol.8) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- "The Syntax and Logic of Imperatives" Aug.- Sept. 1961 (Vol.8) "Semantic Notes- Imperatives" Dec. 1961 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- "Relativity in Ethics" Jan. 1960, through "Appendix I: The Ultimate Ground of Empirical Knowledge" May 1960 (Vol. 9) (Box 5, Folder 10)
- "Chapter 2: Introduction; Ethics and Theory of Ethics" Apr. 1960, through "Critique of Knowledge" Oct. 1960 (Vol. 9) (Box 5, Folder 11)
- "Chapter 2: Introduction; Semantics of the Imperative" May 1960, through "Why do men Associate?" Mar. 1960 (Vol. 9) (Box 5, Folder 12)
- "Chapter 5: The Right" and "Right Doing and Right Thinking" (Vol. 10) (Box 5, Folder 13)
- "The Good" and "On Goodness and Badness in Experience" (Vol. 10) (Box 6, Folder 1)
- "Personal Good", "Belief in Other Humans", and "On the Immediately Good" (Box 6, Folder 2)
- "On the Technical, Prudential, and Moral", "Mostly about Relativism in Ethics and the Cynical", and "About Maxims" (Vol. 11) (Box 6, Folder 3)
- "On Ethics and Prudence", "Kant--Free Will", and "Miscellaneous Items on Desire, Prudence, and Happiness" (Vol. 11) (Box 6, Folder 4)
- "On the Moral, Prudential, and Technical", "On the Rightness of Social Organization", "On the narrow and the wide...", and "On Prudence (Vol. 11) (Box 6, Folder 5)
- "On Obligations to Others and Prudence" (Vol. 11a) (Box 6, Folder 6)
- "Rejects and Drafts for Ch. 1", and "More on the Technical, Prudential, and Moral" (Vol. 11a) (Box 6, Folder 7)
- "Saved Jottings" (Vol. 12) (Box 6, Folder 8)
- "Saved Jottings" (Vol. 12) (Box 6, Folder 9)
- "What Good is Ethics?..." Oct. - Nov. 1958 (Vol. 13) (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Jottings on Ethics Mar.-Jun. 1959 (Vol. 14) (Box 6, Folder 11)
- "Foundations of Ethics" Apr. - July 1959 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- "Foundations of Ethics" May - July 1959 (Vol. 14a) (Box 7, Folder 1)
- "Foundations of Ethics" As Presented October 1959 (Vol. 14b) (Box 7, Folder 2)
- "Foundations of Ethics" Mar. - Apr. 1959 (Vol. 14c) (Box 7, Folder 3)
- "Foundations of Ethics" Sept. 1959 (Vol. 14c) (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Letter Course on "Value Theory" at Michigan State Univ. 1958 (Vol. 15) (Box 7, Folder 5)
- "The Categorical Imperative" delivered at Michigan State University July 24, 1958 (Vol. 15) (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Writings on Ethics 1958 (Vol. 16) (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Writings on Ethics 1958 (Vol. 16a) (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Final Typed draft of Our Social Inheritance (Vol. 19) (Box 8, Folder 1)
- "Ethics and Social Order" Oct. 1956, and Letter to W: H. Werkmeister 1957, Volume 19 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Writings on Ethics Fall 1956 and Students and Seminar topics at Harvard Volume 18 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Jottings made at the Institute for Advances Study in the Behavioral Sciences Stanford, Ca. Fall 1957 (Vol. 17) (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Lectures on Theory of Value Stanford Univ. 1955 & 1956 (Vol.20) (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Lectures on Theory of Value Stanford Univ. 1955 & 1956 (Vol. 20) (Box 8, Folder 6)
- "Philosophy and Science" (Vol. 21) (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Draft of Our Social Inheritance (Vol. 21) (Box 8, Folder 8)
- The Right: Lectures given at Stanford University (Box 8, Folder 9)
- The Right: Lectures given at Stanford University (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Draft of the Woodbridge Lectures Delivered at Columbia University Nov. 1954 (Vol. 22x) (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Draft of the Woodbridge Lectures Delivered at Columbia University Nov. 1954 (Vol. 22x) (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Lectures on "Ethics and Human Nature" Princeton Outlines 1954 (Vol. 23) (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Lectures on "Ethics and Human Nature" Princeton Outlines 1954 (Vol. 23) (Box 9, Folder 5)
- "A paradox of Nomalism" June 1953, through "On the ground and Validity of Moral Principles: June 1953 (Vol. 24) (Box 9, Folder 6)
- On Criticism July 1953, "What is Philosophy?" Feb. 1954 (Vol. 24) (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Proseminar Lectures on "Practical Philosophy" Harvard University 1952 (Vol. 23) (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Proseminar Lectures on "Practical Philosophy" Harvard University 1952 (Vol. 25a) (Box 9, Folder 9)
- "Science and Ethics" Jan. 1952, through "Ethics in the Age of Science" Apr. 1952 (Vol. 25x) (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Outline for a Book on Ethics July 1951, through On Loyalty no date (Vol. 26) (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Various Versions of an Introduction to his Ethics Book Feb. 1951 through "The Geometry of Living" no date (Vol. 27) (Box 10, Folder 2)
- "Introduction" to his Ethics Book June 1951, through Second Version of. "Valuation and the Good" July 1951, (Vol. 27) (Box 10, Folder 3)
- "Outlines of Lectures" on Ethics Harvard University July - Dec. 1951 (Vol. 28) (Box 10, Folder 4)
- "Outlines of Lectures" on Ethics Harvard University July- Dec. 1951 (Vol. 28) (Box 10, Folder 5)
- "Persuasive Definition and Scientific Theory" no date, and "Replaced Drafts" Summer 1951 (Vol. 29) (Box 10, Folder 6)
- A Lecture given at Johns Hopkins University on Ethics 1954 through Second Version of "The Nature of Value" Apr. 15, 1954, (Vol. 30) (Box 10, Folder 7)
- "What is Philosophy?" before 1954? through "The Conceptual and the Material in Logic and Philosophy" 1948? (Vol. 30) (Box 10, Folder 8)
- "The Hard Core of Pragmatism" Apr. 29, 1954, through "The Empirical Basis of Value-Judgements" Apr. 1950 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- "Turning Points in Ethics" Machete Lectures Wesleyan University 1952 (Vol. 31) (Box 11, Folder 2)
- "Practical and Moral Imperatives" 1949, "Values and Facts" 1952, "The Rational Imperatives" 1952 (Vol. 32) (Box 11, Folder 3)
- "Introduction" To a book on Ethics 1948, "Chapter two" 1949 (Vol. 34) (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous papers 1950, through Fragments 1952, (Vol. 34) (Box 11, Folder 5)
- On the Rightness of Acts 1950, through an Interpretation of the Categorical Imperative Sept. 1950 (Vol. 33) (Box 11, Folder 6)
- "The Classification of Acts" 1950, through Continuation of "Right" Sept. 1950 (Vol. 33) (Box 11, Folder 7)
- "Relativity of Values": Chapter two 1949, "Physical and Social Science" July 1949, (Vol. 35) (Box 11, Folder 8)
- "J.S. Mill - Personal Liberty and Social Order" July 1949, through On Human Goods, July 1948 (Vol. 35) (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Course Syllabi: 1946-47 Harvard University, through "The Objectivity of Value-Judgements" April 1941, (Vol. 37) (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Course Lectures on: "Social Ethics" Harvard University and Course outlines for Phil. E (Vol 38) (Box 12, Folder 2)
- "Introduction: Subjective and Objective Right" Aug. 1948, through "Chapter two: The Field of Ethics" Dec. 1948, (Vol. 36) (Box 12, Folder 3)
- 2nd draft of: "Chapter two: The Field of Ethics" Sept. 1948, and "The Imperative and the Normative" July 1948, (Vol. 36) (Box 12, Folder 4)
- "Logical Positivism and Pragmatism" (Vol. 39) (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Lecture course on the Theory of Knowledge Philosophy 10, Lecture Course on Ethics, Harvard University (Vol. 40) (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Lecture Course on the Theory of Knowledge, Lecture Course on Ethics Philosophy B, Harvard University (Vol. 40) (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Lecture Course on Metaphysics, Epistemology, etc. Philosophy B, Harvard University (Vol. 41) (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Lecture Course on Ethics Philosophy B, Harvard University (Vol. 41) (Box 12, Folder 9)
- On Empirical Knowledge, "Chapter Two: Types of Meaning and types of Truth," Second draft of Ch. 2. (Vol. 42) (Box 12, Folder 10)
- "Chapter Two: The Meaning of Some familiar expressions", "Relativity of Values" (Vol. 42) (Box 12, Folder 11)
- "Note about Connotation and Denotation," Two Basic Principles of Ethics, (Vol. 42) (Box 13, Folder 1)
- An Analysis of Knowledge and Valuation: (Vol. 43) (Box 13, Folder 2)
- An Analysis of Knowledge and Valuation: (Vol. 43) (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Book II Empirical Knowledge (Vol. 44) (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Book II Empirical Knowledge (Vol. 44) (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Writings, "Inherent Value and the Esthetic" 1945, through "Judgements of Value and judgements of Facts" 1936 (Vol. 1) (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Writings, "Mind and the World Order" Chapter I (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Writings, "Mind and the World Order" Chapter II (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Writings, "Mind and the World Order" Chapter III (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Writings, "Mind and the World Order" Chapter IV (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Writings, "Mind and the World Order" Chapter V (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Writings, "Mind and the World Order" Chapter VI (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Writings, "Mind and the World Order" Chapter VII (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Writings, "Mind and the World Order" Chapter VIII (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Writings, "Mind and the World Order" Chapter IX (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Writings, "Mind and the World Order" Chapter X (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Writings, "Mind and the World Order" Chapter XI (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Writings: "The Moral Sense..." (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Writings: "Loose Pieces" (Vol. 1) (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Writings: "Loose Pieces" (Vol. 2) (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Writings: "Loose Pieces" (Vol. 3) (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Writings: "Loose Pieces" (Vol. 4) (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Loose Pieces, Early draft of: Analysis of Knowledge and Valuation (Vol. 5) (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Loose Pieces (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Notes taken by Lewis in a Logic Course (Phil. 15) Harvard University 1909, (Vol. 1) (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Witings Lecture Notes (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Notes taken by Lewis in a Seminary in Logic: The Concept of Causation Harvard University 1909-10 (Vol. 3) (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Lecture Courses on: Philosophies of Social Relations Logical Theory University of California, Berkeley 1911-1920 (Vol. 4) (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Notes taken by Lewis, "Post-Kantian Idealism" Fall 1920 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Religious Feeling and Religious Theory (Box 15, Folder 6)
- "Abstract of First Carus Lecture Disturbed in Advance" University of California, Berkeley Dec. 1945 (Vol. 1) (Box 16, Folder 1)
- "Outline of a New Approach to the Calculus of Propositional Functions" (Vol. 2) (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Lecture Course on Metaphysics Harvard University no date, (vol. 3) (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Lecture Course on Greek Philosophy Harvard University no date, (Vol. 4) (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Lecture Course on Greek Philosophy (continued) Harvard University no date, (Vol. 5) (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Lecture Course on Philosophy no date, (Vol. 6) (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Lecture Course on Nineteenth Century Philosophy, Harvard University no date, (Vol. 7) (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Writing Lecture Notes, Columbia University, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Writing Lecture Notes, Harvard University, 1922-23 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Writing Lecture Notes, Harvard University, 1922-23 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Writings William Moody Lecture, Univ. of Chicago May 11, 1932. (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Writing Lect. Notes Harvard University, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Lewis, C.I. Writings: Philosophy B lecture notes (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Lewis, C.I. Writings: Philosophy B, 1A lecture notes, ca. 1935 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Lewis, C.I. Writings: Philosophy B, 1A lecture notes, ca. 1935 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Lecture Course on Ethics Harvard University no date, (Vol. 1) (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Lecture notes (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Lecture course on Logic Harvard University, no date (Vol. 3) (Box 18, Folder 3)
- A Summary of Carnap's Logische Aufbau der Welt (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Reprints of Articles, (Vol. 5) (Box 18, Folder 5)
- On Symbolic Logic, (Vol. 6) (Box 18, Folder 6)
- In Memoriam: Ralph Barton Perry (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Translations(?), Logical Analysis of the Concept of Probability, Walsmann, "Causation and Probability" Reichenbach (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Basic Elements of Probability Theory: "Permutations and Combinations" Excerpts from the Philosophy and History of Science, (Vol. 9) (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Symbolic Logic Tables (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Reprints (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Reprints About Lewis (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Misc. Pieces (Box 18, Folder 13)
- 3" by 5" Card Box arranged in Alphabetical order by topic for Ground and Nature of the Right (Box 19, Folder 1)
- 3" by 5" Card Box arranged in Alphabetical order by topic for Ground and Nature of the Right (Box 19, Folder 2)
- The C.I. Lewis Materials; A Survey (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Remarks, Notes... (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Summaries etc. (Box 19, Folder 5)
- "Preface- and Confession" (Box 19, Folder 6)
- "Good and Bad in Experience" (Box 19, Folder 7)
- "Good and Bad in Experience:Prolegomena" (Box 19, Folder 8)
- The Field of Ethics Large Selection of Late Lewis Material (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Chapter I Introduction. (About Philosophy in General and ethics in Particular, plus some appendix pages.) (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Ethics and Theory of Ethics Chapter II (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Semantics of the Imperative (Chapter II?) (Box 19, Folder 12)
- "Ethics anf the Logical" (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Deliberate Acts Chapter II (Box 20, Folder 2)
- The Normative Right Acts and Good Acts (Chapter IV?) (Box 20, Folder 3)
- "Right doing and the Right to do" (Chapter V? More Likely IV) (Box 20, Folder 4)
- "We approach the Normative Finalities" (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Plan-Related Materials (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Foundations of Ethics, Wesleyan Lectures, Oct. 1959 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Journal of the History of Philosophy July, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Harvard University Gazette (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Correspondence 1953,1966 (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Journals 1964 (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Articles and Journals 1939-1952 (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Xeroxes of articles by Fernando Molina, A reconstruction of Professor C.I. Lewis' Lectures on Immanuel Kant's Critique of Pure Reason (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Xeroxes of articles by Fernando Molina, Abstract: C.I. Lewis' Notebook on Kant, 1910-11 (Box 20, Folder 14)
- Abstract: A Reconstruction of C.I. Lewis' Lectures on Epistemology Molina Gift, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 15)
- Abstract: Notes by C.I. Lewis on Royce's Theory of Categories, Molina Gift 1982 (Box 20, Folder 16)
- Abstract: Notes by C.I. Lewis on Empirical Knowledge, Phenomenology, and Related Topics Molina Gift 1982 (Box 20, Folder 17)
- Kant's Theory of Ethics ABBOTT, Sixth Edition, 1927 (Box 21)
- Principles Hylas and Philonous G. Berkeley, 1907 (Box 21)
- Kant's Critique of Judgement, translated by J.H. Bernard 1931 (Box 21)
- On Method, Meditations Descartes, 1903 (Box 21)
- Human Understanding Locke, 1906 (Box 22)
- Human Understanding Principles of Morals Hume, 1907 (Box 22)
- Ethics and Language Stevenson, 1945 (Box 22)
- Symbolic Logic Lewis & Langford, 1932 (Box 22)
- Symbolic Logic Lewis & Langford, 1932 (Box 23)
- Kant's Critique of Pure Reason, 1911 (Box 23)
- The Language of Morals Hare, 1952 (Box 23)
- The Definition of Good, Ewing, 1947 (Box 23)
- Immanuel Kant's Critique of Pure Reason Norman Kemp Smith, 1929 (Box 23)
- The Concept of Morals, Stace, 1937 (Box 23)
- Logic and the Basis of Ethics Prior, 1949 (Box 23)
- Dewey: Valuation 1939 (Box 23)
- Morris: Theory of signs 1938 (Box 23)
- Semantics and the Philosophy of Language Linsky 1952 (Box 23)
- Problems of Ethics Moritz Schlick 1939 (Box 23)
- The Concept of Nature Whitehead, 1920 (Box 23)
- Leibniz Discourse on Metaphysics, 1902 (Box 23)
- Fact, Fiction, and Forecast, Goodman, 1955 (Box 23)
- The Principles of Natural Knowledge, Whitehead, 1919 (Box 23)
- Process and Reality, Whitehead, 1929 (Box 23)
- The Right and The Good, Ross, 1930 (Box 23)
- Lectures on Ethics Immanuel Kant, 1930 (Box 23)
- Principia Ethica, Moore, 1922 (Box 23)
- Ethics P.H. Nowell-Smith, 1954 (Box 23)
- The Quest for Certainty, Dewey, 1929 (Box 23)